{"tossups": [{"question": "Samantha Power wrote a book about U.S. policy regarding this action, which she called \u201cthe problem from hell.\u201d Efrain Rios Montt was indicted for participation in one of these events in Guatemala. In 1995, one of these actions at (*) Srebrenica (sreh-breh-NEET-sah) resulted in Operation Deliberate Force, a bombing campaign that targeted Bosnian Serb forces. The Soviet Union perpetrated one of these events in Ukraine through a famine in an event known as the Holodomor. What type of mass murder, for 10 points, resulted in the death of hundreds of thousands of Tutsis in Rwanda?", "answer": "Genocide [accept equivalents such as ethnic cleansing; prompt on \u201cmass murder\u201d until mentioned; prompt on \u201cmassacre\u201d]", "subcategory": "World History", "category": "History"}, {"question": "This idea can be proven using time symmetry along with Noether\u2019s theorem. The relative speed of a body is proportional to two over the distance between the bodies because of an application of this idea, called the Vis Viva equation. The escape velocity can be found by applying this idea to (*) gravity, and this idea is applied in fluid dynamics as Bernoulli\u2019s Law. One law that is derived from this idea states that U equals Q minus W, and that law is the first law of thermodynamics. For 10 points, name this idea in physics that the total amount of energy in a closed system is constant.", "answer": "Conservation of Energy [prompt on partial answer]", "subcategory": "Physics", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "The Prose Edda refers to both this figure, as well as Odin, as the father of Vali. This brother of Helblindi and Byleistr begins flying with the other gods after they ostracize him for killing the servant Fimafeng. On a mission to Jotunheim, this deity accompanies a (*) cross-dressing Thor. This god\u2019s son, Narfi, is turned into a wolf, while his other son\u2019s entrails are used to bind him for killing Baldr, whereupon he is placed underneath a serpent that drips venom on him. For 10 points, name this Norse trickster god, the father of Hel, Fenrir, Jormungandr, and the eight-legged horse, Sleipnir.", "answer": "Loki", "category": "Mythology"}, {"question": "One work by this philosopher uses the example of a group of lepers and the image of the Ship of Fools to contrast the difference between old and new treatments of people with illnesses. This philosopher also describes how modern doctors dehumanize their patients with the \u201cmedical gaze\u201d in his work The Birth of the Clinic. (*) This philosopher\u2019s The Order of Things opens with an analysis of the painting Las Meninas, and he describes an empathetic disconnect because of the decrease of public executions in his work Discipline and Punish. For 10 points, name this French philosopher who wrote The History of Sexuality and Madness and Civilization.", "answer": "Michel Foucault", "category": "Philosophy"}, {"question": "In one novel written in this language, a colonel on a walk recognizes a dog that was previously stolen from him. In a play written in this language, Helena Glory marries Domin and burns the formula created by Rossum. That play, R.U.R., saw the first recorded instance of the word (*) \u201crobot.\u201d In another work written in this language, Sabina learns that Tereza and Tomas died in a car crash; that book is The Unbearable Lightness of Being. For 10 points, name this language used by Jaroslav Hasek, Karel Capek, and Milan Kundera, who wrote about the Prague Spring.", "answer": "Czech language", "subcategory": "European Literature", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "Abras are traditionally used to ferry people across this city\u2019s namesake creek. This city beat out Sao Paulo, Izmir, and Yekaterinburg to host the Expo 2020. Terminal 3 of this city\u2019s international airport is the largest airport terminal in the world. This city, which forms a metropolitan area with Sharjah and Ajman, contains a (*) hotel that is considered to be the \u201cworld\u2019s only seven-star\u201d hotel. It\u2019s not in the Bahamas, but an Atlantis Resort in this city is situated on a manmade island shaped like a palm tree. Containing the tallest building in the world, the Burj Khalifa, is, for 10 points, what city in the United Arab Emirates?", "answer": "Dubai", "category": "Geography"}, {"question": "One character is driven to commit suicide in this fashion after being manipulated by Edmund Hooper for years. Another character who attempts to kill herself in this way begins to visit the female prisoners at Millbank prison to help her overcome her depression in the novel (*) Affinity. Another character who dies in this way leaves a brief suicide note that reads: \u201cI didn\u2019t mean it\u201d; that character is Ilse Lubin. Clyde Griffiths utilizes this method to murder Roberta Alden in Theodore Dreiser\u2019s An American Tragedy, and Ophelia uses it to kill herself in Shakespeare\u2019s Hamlet. For 10 points, name this water-based method of death.", "answer": "Drowning [accept word forms]", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "The red, blue, and green rooms in this building were originally set in the French Empire style and served as its three state parlors. Designed by James Hoban, this building underwent major renovations commissioned by (*) Theodore Roosevelt and John F. Kennedy. Its West Wing contains major executive offices including one called the Oval Office. For 10 points, name this official residence of the President of the United States that was set ablaze in 1814.", "answer": "White House", "subcategory": "American History", "category": "History"}, {"question": "At a location described by this adjective, fire ships were successfully used by Huang Gai to burn down Cao Cao\u2019s fleet. After being subjected to the Fifth Encirclement Campaign, a military force described by this adjective was forced to retreat from (*) Jiangxi to Shaanxi. This is the first of two adjectives that describes a rebellion led by White Lotus society member Zhu Yuanzhang, who then became the Hongwu emperor. For 10 points, a \u201cturban\u201d rebellion that overthrew the Yuan Dynasty and Mao Zedong\u2019s communist army were described by what color?", "answer": "Red", "subcategory": "World History", "category": "History"}, {"question": "This language was invented by Tim Berners-Lee, and initially released in 1993. This language supports the Unicode and ASCII (ask-ee) character sets through the use of UTF-8 and 16 encoding and was extended in 2000 with a variation that implements XML markup standards. The W3C is responsible for updating and maintaining this language, which uses (*) CSS to change the appearance of constructs created with it and SQL (sequel) to allow for database access. This language recently released a fifth revision intended to supersede some functionalities of Adobe\u2019s Flash Player. For 10 points, name this markup language used to design websites?", "answer": "HTML or HyperText Markup Language", "subcategory": "Other Science", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "A Dictabelt recording from a police motorcyclist\u2019s open microphone spawned many conspiracies about this event but was debunked because of the sound of vehicles rushing to Parkland Hospital after it occurred. Another well-known recording of this event is (*) Abraham Zapruder\u2019s silent film of this event. Governor John Connally was struck by a \u201csingle bullet\u201d that also struck the target of this event. That single bullet theory originated from the Warren Commission, which investigated, for 10 points, what event, that resulted in the death of the thirty-fifth President on November 22, 1963 in Dallas?", "answer": "Assassination of John F. Kennedy [accept synonyms for assassination and accept JFK for J. Kennedy, prompt on answers that only include \u201cKennedy\u201d; do NOT accept or prompt on mentions of Robert Kennedy]", "subcategory": "American History", "category": "History"}, {"question": "A James Thomson poem inspired this man to paint a scene in which humans can be seen thronging around the title structure in his Fountain of Indolence. \u201cThe flag which braved the battle and the breeze / No longer owns her\u201d was ascribed to a ship being towed away after the Battle of (*) Trafalgar in one of this artist\u2019s paintings. People dispute whether a white rabbit can be seen on the Maidenhead Bridge in one of this artist\u2019s paintings, which shows a train appearing from the distance. For 10 points, name this English artist of Rain, Steam, and Speed.", "answer": "Joseph Mallord William Turner", "subcategory": "Visual Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts"}, {"question": "A character in this play performed in The Pirates of Penzance and was romantically involved with Emily Meisenbach. Another character is nauseated by her class at Rubicam's Business College and skips class to visit the penguins at the zoo. The protagonist\u2019s brother in this work is frustrated with his job at a shoe warehouse and goes to the (*) movies nearly every night, infuriating his mother. That mother, Amanda, boasts of a Sunday in Blue Mountain when she received seventeen gentlemen callers. For 10 points, name this play in which the crippled Laura shows the title collection to her high school love, Jim O\u2019 Connor, by Tennessee Williams.", "answer": "The Glass Menagerie", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "This process begins in the ori-C region in bacteria. Separation of catenanes is facilitated by an enzyme that also reduces torsional stress during this process. That enzyme is called topoisomerase. An experiment that used a heavy isotope of nitrogen to show that this process is semiconservative is named for (*) Meselson and Stahl. Okazaki fragments form on the lagging strand during this process because of DNA polymerase\u2019s inability to work in the three prime to five prime direction. For 10 points, name this process that occurs in the S phase of the cell cycle and duplicates a cell\u2019s genome.", "answer": "DNA Replication [accept DNA Synthesis or equivalents]", "subcategory": "Biology", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "A powerful lawyer in this novel incessantly washes his hands to prevent criminal corruption from tainting him. The protagonist of this novel is nicknamed Handel by his friend, Herbert Pocket, because of his former experience as a blacksmith. That protagonist\u2019s wealthy and mysterious benefactor is revealed to be the escaped (*) convict Abel Magwitch. In this work, the eccentric Miss Havisham inhabits a room full of stopped clocks and raises her adopted daughter Estella to break the hearts of men. For 10 points, name this novel that follows the development of the orphan Pip, by Charles Dickens.", "answer": "Great Expectations", "subcategory": "British Literature", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "In May of 2017, a lumberjack wielding biochemical weapons was allegedly hired to assassinate this man. This figure was reportedly enrolled in the International Baccalaureate in a Swiss school under an alias but it is unclear whether he received a diploma. (*) Dramatic photos of this man are commonly broadcasted by the KCNA to intimidate his enemies. This biggest fan of Michael Jordan had his uncle Jang Song-Thaek executed for treason. For 10 points, name this eternal first-secretary of the Democratic People\u2019s Republic of Korea.", "answer": "Kim Jong-Un", "subcategory": "World History", "category": "History"}, {"question": "Samson told a riddle about this creature in which he said \u201cOut of the eater, something to eat\u201d shortly after tearing apart one of these animals. One man asked not to be killed in the day or night or on the ground or sky and was subsequently killed by a half-man, half this animal. That half-human creature was the fourth avatar of Vishnu, called (*) Narasimha. An angel sealed the jaws of these animals after Darius the Mede was tricked into condemning a servant to death. For 10 points, Daniel was thrown into a den containing what wild animals, from which he escaped unscathed?", "answer": "Lions", "category": "Mythology"}, {"question": "One work of this type takes its name come from the German word for piano and starts with a series of chords in B Flat Major and later in D Major. Another work of this type was known as \u201cAppassionata.\u201d Lebewohl were the words to the first three chords in one type of this work that was written for the fleeing of Archduke (*) Randolph. Along with \u201cLes Adieux,\u201d one work of this type features an adagio sostenuto first movement where the right hand plays triplets and was nicknamed \u201cQuasi una Fantasia.\u201d For 10 points, name this type of work which includes a \u201cMoonlight\u201d variety written by Beethoven.", "answer": "Sonata", "subcategory": "Auditory Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts"}, {"question": "This quantity can be found for a compound by taking the geometric mean of its values for the individual atoms, and ionization energy and electron affinity can be averaged to calculate this quantity. This quantity is defined through the use of effective nuclear charge on the (*) Allred-Rochow scale, which is taken over the radius squared to yield this quantity\u2019s value on that scale. Measuring 4.0 for fluorine on the Pauling scale, for 10 points, name this quantity that measures the ability of an atom to attract electrons.", "answer": "Electronegativity", "subcategory": "Chemistry", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "Rudi Dutschke argued for a \u201clong march through the institutions of power\u201d as part of an ongoing social movement in this country. The Basic Treaty lowered tensions between this country and its eastern neighbor, and it allowed both of them to enter the United Nations. Gunter Guillaume spied on this country while working as an agent for another country\u2019s (*) Stasi. Under the advice of economic minister Ludwig Erhard, this country experienced an \u201ceconomic miracle\u201d under its first chancellor Konrad Adenauer. For 10 points, name this country whose communist eastern neighbor surrounded Berlin.", "answer": "West Germany [prompt on \u201cGermany\u201d; do NOT prompt on or accept \u201cEast Germany\u201d] Tiebreaker", "subcategory": "European History", "category": "History"}, {"question": "This author begins a poem with \u201cIt was a long time ago / I have almost forgotten my dream,\u201d and loses the dream because \u201cthe wall rose / rose slowly / slowly / between me and my dream.\u201d This author of \u201cMother to Son\u201d often talks about dreams, saying in the poem (*) \u201cDreams\u201d that \u201cif dreams die / Life is a broken-winged bird / that cannot fly.\u201d This author\u2019s poem \u201cHarlem\u201d is also known as \u201cDream Deferred\u201d because of its opening line, \u201cWhat happens to a dream deferred?\u201d For 10 points, name this leader of the Harlem Renaissance, the author of \u201cThe Negro Speaks of Rivers\u201d and \u201cThe Weary Blues.\u201d", "answer": "Langston Hughes Packet 10 \u2013 Bonuses", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature"}], "bonuses": [{"leadin": "One stanza of this poem mentions \u201cA Book of Verses underneath the Bough\u201d and \u201cA Jug of Wine, a Loaf of Bread-- and Thou.\u201d For 10 points each:", "answers": ["Rubaiyat of Omar Khayyam", "Quatrains", "Eugene O\u2019Neill"], "parts": ["Name this selection of ancient Persian poems originally written by Omar Khayyam that was later translated and given its title by Edward FitzGerald.", "The Rubaiyat is known for these kinds of stanzas which typically have four lines and alternating rhyming schemes.", "The last line of the Rubaiyat\u2019s Quatrain XII, \u201cO, Wilderness were Paradise enow!\u201d inspired the title of this playwright\u2019s play Ah, Wilderness!"], "subcategory": "World Literature", "category": "Literature"}, {"leadin": "For 10 points each, answer some questions about French attempts to colonize Africa:", "answers": ["Madagascar", "Algeria", "Sudan"], "parts": ["This island\u2019s queen Ranavalona III was stripped of all authority after the French annexed it in 1896. The Nazis suggested this island as a deportation site for Jews before the Holocaust was implemented.", "This country was annexed by the French after two of their consuls were disrespected by a local dey. This country later gained its independence when Charles de Gaulle signed the Evian Accords.", "This country was the site of a border dispute between the French and British in its city of Fashoda. Lord Kitchener defeated the Mahdist forces at the Battle of Omdurman in this country."], "subcategory": "World History", "category": "History"}, {"leadin": "For 10 points each, answer some questions regarding Caribbean resort towns:", "answers": ["Cancun", "San Juan", "Montego Bay"], "parts": ["This resort town on the Yucatan Peninsula was visited by approximately five million tourists in 2015. You can travel to the nearby islands of Isla Mujeres and Cozumel from it.", "Visitors to this capital of Puerto Rico can visit its fortress of El Morro. You can also see Taino petroglyphs in the nearby tropical rainforest of El Yunque.", "Visitors can fly into this Jamaican city through Donald Sangster International Airport. Its most popular beach is known as the Doctor\u2019s Cave Beach."], "category": "Geography"}, {"leadin": "There are dispersive and reflective types of these devices. For 10 points each:", "answers": ["Prism", "Index of Refraction", "Chromatic aberration [prompt on partial answer]"], "parts": ["Name these devices that split white light into its component colors. Water droplets act like these devices during rainbows.", "Prisms are able to split light because the different wavelengths of light have different values for this quantity symbolized n. This quantity is the ratio of the velocity of light in a vacuum to that in a particular medium.", "Different wavelengths of light having different indices of refractions can be a problem because of this phenomenon, where the lens fails to focus all the colors at one point."], "subcategory": "Physics", "category": "Science"}, {"leadin": "Prehistoric paintings provide an insight into the lives of early humans. For 10 points each:", "answers": ["Bull", "Charcoal", "Stencil"], "parts": ["Early cave paintings depict several animals, including this horned bovine. The Lascaux Caves have a Great Hall named for these animals, showing their importance to early humans as a source of food.", "At Lascaux and other prehistoric sites, ochre, a kind of pigment, was used to color the animals while this substance was used to create a dark outline.", "Some paintings consisted of ochre that was blown onto a hand on the cave wall, producing a negative handprint. Their hands represent one of the first uses of this tool, an object around which pigment is sprayed to produce a consistent pattern."], "category": "Science"}, {"leadin": "Let\u2019s talk about prophets. For 10 points each:", "answers": ["Isaiah", "Haile Selassie", "Joseph Smith"], "parts": ["This prophet\u2019s namesake book in the Old Testament predicts the birth of Christ and the Jewish captivity in Babylon. He discussed a time of peace when people may beat their swords into plowshares.", "The day this man visited Jamaica is marked as a Nyabinghi Assembly in Rastafarianism. This man, who was given the title of \u201cConquering Lion of the Tribe of Judah,\u201d was descended from Solomon.", "This man was led to two seer stones by an angel, allowing him to translate the reformed Egyptian that the holy text of the Church of the Latter Day Saints originally was written in."], "category": "Religion"}, {"leadin": "For 10 points each, answer these questions about scordatura, the purposeful mistuning of strings.", "answers": ["Tritone [accept Augmented Fourth or Diminished fifth]", "Johann Pachelbel", "Fiddle [prompt on \u201cViolin\u201d]"], "parts": ["Often, scordatura is used to play intervals that would otherwise be too cumbersome to play. For example, in Saint-Saens's Danse Macabre, the violins tune their E-strings to E-flat in order to play a chord of this interval. This interval, nicknamed \u201cthe Devil in music,\u201d is found between the two notes F and B.", "This composer\u2019s Musikalische Erg\u00f6tzung suite was specifically written for mistuned violins. This composer, however, is more well-known for his famous Canon in D, often used at weddings.", "This American variant of a common stringed-instrument, often used in folk tunes, can use special \u201ccross-tunings\u201d to allow for easier playing of chords. Some such tunings include \u201cCajun,\u201d \u201cSawmill,\u201d and \u201cGlory in the Meeting House.\u201d"], "subcategory": "Auditory Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts"}, {"leadin": "Daisy and Tom live in East Egg in this novel. For 10 points each:", "answers": ["The Great Gatsby", "F. Scott Fitzgerald", "Tender is the Night"], "parts": ["Identify this novel, in which Nick Carraway lives in West Egg next to the mysterious title character.", "This author of The Great Gatsby also wrote This Side of Paradise and Tales of the Jazz Age.", "This other Fitzgerald work focuses on a seventeen-year-old actress as she visits the Riviera with her mother and meets a cast of not-so-colorful characters, including Luis Campion, Mrs. Abrams, and Dick and Nicole Diver."], "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature"}, {"leadin": "For 10 points each, answer these questions about chromosomal abnormalities.", "answers": ["Trisomy", "Down\u2019s syndrome [accept Trisomy 21]", "Nondisjunction"], "parts": ["This condition results from an extra copy of a chromosome being present in the cell\u2019s nuclei, can cause multiple disorders, and takes its name from the fact that there are three chromosomes.", "This disorder is caused by a partial or full third copy of chromosome twenty-one. Symptoms include physical characteristics such as slanted eyes and a flat nasal bridge, as well as mild to severe cases of intellectual disability.", "The extra copy of chromosome twenty-one present in Down\u2019s syndrome occurs because of this mutation during meiosis that prevents the separation of homologous chromosomes during anaphase."], "subcategory": "Biology", "category": "Science"}, {"leadin": "James Renshaw Cox led a group of twenty-five thousand armed protesters against the government during this period. For 10 points each:", "answers": ["Great Depression", "New Deal", "Tennessee Valley Authority"], "parts": ["Name this worst economic downturn in American history. This period began with the Stock Market Crash of 1929.", "To counteract the problems of the Great Depression, FDR passed this series of legislation that employed several people as part of the Works Progress Administration and the Public Works Administration. It also created the FDIC.", "This New Deal agency, which was spearheaded by George W. Norris, generated energy for the namesake region. It began as an effort to build a power plant at Muscle Shoals."], "subcategory": "American History", "category": "History"}, {"leadin": "We are able to write myth questions because many traditions have been documented in written sources. For 10 points each:", "answers": ["The Metamorphoses", "Pyramus and Thisbe [in any order]", "Arachne"], "parts": ["Name this Latin epic of transformations by Ovid that has been plundered for plot devices by Boccaccio, Dante, Chaucer, and Shakespeare. Its author hoped to create a work that would rival The Aeneid.", "Shakespeare notably took inspiration for Romeo and Juliet from the story of these two star-crossed lovers. In Ovid\u2019s telling, one takes his own life after thinking the other was eaten by a lion. They notably communicated via a crack in a wall.", "In another episode of the Metamorphoses, this woman of Lydia challenges Athena to a weaving contest. Although this woman technically wins, Athena transforms her into a spider anyway."], "subcategory": "British Literature", "category": "Literature"}, {"leadin": "The Cradle of Civilization lies in the Middle East. For 10 points each:", "answers": ["Mesopotamia", "Assyria [accept Assyrian empire]", "Hittites"], "parts": ["Name this geographical region, Greek for \u201cbetween the two rivers.\u201d This region is traditionally considered to be the home of the first civilizations like Sumeria. The two rivers referenced are the Tigris and the Euphrates.", "This extraordinarily brutal civilization with capitals at Assur and Nineveh conquered Babylon. Famous kings of it include Ashurbanipal, Sennacherib, and Tiglath-Pileser, who flayed their enemies alive.", "This Bronze-Age Anatolian civilization was halted by Assyrian armies in their advance on Mesopotamia. Nonetheless, their chariots conquered modern-day Syria."], "subcategory": "World History", "category": "History"}, {"leadin": "Authors sometimes adapt and rewrite works of literature written by other people. For 10 points each:", "answers": ["Wide Sargasso Sea", "Rosencrantz and Guildenstern are Dead", "Margaret Atwood"], "parts": ["Dominican author Jean Rhys wrote this novel, a prequel to Jane Eyre by Charlotte Bronte. This novel follows the life of Antoinette Cosway, who becomes the madwoman Bertha Mason.", "In an absurdist retelling of Shakespeare\u2019s Hamlet, Tom Stoppard wrote about these two title couriers attempting to make sense of the main events of Hamlet, which leads to their own executions.", "This Canadian author rewrote Homer\u2019s The Odyssey from the perspective of Odysseus\u2019 wife in The Penelopiad. This author also wrote The Handmaid\u2019s Tale."], "subcategory": "British Literature", "category": "Literature"}, {"leadin": "For 10 points each, identify these things related to the hit television series <em>Friends</em>.", "answers": ["Jennifer Aniston", "Phoebe Buffay [accept either]", "Central Perk"], "parts": ["This actress, the first wife of Brad Pitt, played Rachel Green, the socialite turned waitress who has an off-and-on relationship with Ross Geller.", "This eccentric member of the Friends gang is a massage therapist who sings \u201cSmelly Cat,\u201d has a twin sister named Ursula, and becomes a surrogate for her brother Frank.", "The gang always meets in this coffeehouse where Rachel works."], "category": "Trash"}, {"leadin": "Hawking radiation is released by these entities. For 10 points each:", "answers": ["Black holes", "Quasars", "Gravitational Lensing"], "parts": ["Name these entities that are so dense that light cannot escape from them. The event horizon is the boundary of things that can escape their gravitational presence.", "These things form when an accretion disk surrounds a supermassive black hole. They are split into radio-quiet and radio-loud types.", "Massive objects such as black holes and quasars can undergo this effect, in which they curve spacetime, thereby bending the direction of light as a result of gravity."], "subcategory": "Other Science", "category": "Science"}, {"leadin": "This author wrote that a certain work of literature was about \u201cman at war with the hostile world, and his inevitable overthrow with Time.\u201d For 10 points each:", "answers": ["John Ronald Reuel Tolkien [accept JRR Tolkien]", "The Hobbit, or There and Back Again", "The Silmarillion"], "parts": ["Name this writer of \u201cBeowulf: The Monsters and the Critics.\u201d This man\u2019s translation of Beowulf was published in 2014.", "Tolkien is more famous for writing this novel, the prequel to the Lord of the Rings series. In this novel, Bilbo Baggins crosses Middle-Earth in order to fight the dragon Smaug.", "This book, written by Tolkien and published posthumously, details the universe of the Lord of the Rings Series. This book focuses on the First, Second, and Third Ages of Middle-Earth."], "subcategory": "British Literature", "category": "Literature"}, {"leadin": "America led the world in anthropology during the early twentieth century largely because of the genius of one man. For 10 points each:", "answers": ["Franz Boas", "Columbia University", "Margaret Mead"], "parts": ["Name this German-American patriarch who notably developed the \u201cfour-field\u201d subdivision of anthropological study and wrote The Mind of Primitive Man.", "Boas created the field of cultural anthropology at this Ivy-league school in New York that produced such students as Edward Sapir and Ruth Benedict.", "One of Boas\u2019s most famous students was this author of Sex and Temperament in Three Primitive Societies who studied residents on the island of Ta\u2019u in Coming of Age in Samoa."], "category": "Social Science"}, {"leadin": "These elements typically have the lowest first ionization energy. For 10 points each:", "answers": ["Alkali Metals [accept Group 1 or Group IA]", "Electrolysis", "Boron"], "parts": ["Name these elements that are in the first column of the periodic table. They include lithium, sodium and potassium.", "Humphrey Davy discovered sodium through the use of this procedure on sodium hydroxide. This procedure uses electrical current to split apart compounds.", "Sodium is combined with hydrogen and this element in a powerful reducing agent. That compound is synthesized by reacting this element\u2019s trimethyl variety and sodium hydride. This element is also found in Pyrex glassware."], "subcategory": "Chemistry", "category": "Science"}, {"leadin": "\u201cLet those who have been accustomed unjustly to wage private warfare against the faithful now go against the infidels and end with victory this war which should have been begun long ago.\u201d For 10 points each:", "answers": ["Crusades", "Saladin [or Salah ad-Din]", "Seventh Crusade"], "parts": ["Name these series of religious conflicts that began with the aforementioned speech by Pope Urban II at the Council of Clermont in 1095. The first one of these was probably the most successful.", "There were many famous crusaders, but none were as famous as this Ayyubid ruler who opposed them. His genius led to the crushing defeat of the second crusade at the horns of Hattin.", "One of the last crusades launched was this inconclusive expedition led by Louis XI that saw the destruction of the entire French army at Fariskur despite an earlier victory at Damietta."], "subcategory": "European History", "category": "History"}, {"leadin": "For 10 points each, answer these questions about time signatures.", "answers": ["4/4", "2/2", "3/4"], "parts": ["Widely used in modern pop and rock music, this time signature is also referred to as \u201ccommon time\u201d and is denoted with a C.", "This time signature, also called \u201ccut time\u201d is widely used in marches. It is denoted with a C with a vertical line through it.", "Most commonly used in waltzes, mazurkas, and minuets, this time signature gives the quarter note the beat."], "subcategory": "Auditory Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts"}]}